- Let's say you're exploring ways
-假設您正在探索
to improve your company's services.
改善公司服務的方法。
So you collect some survey data,
因此，您可以收集一些調查數據
pull reports on customer retention,
，提取有關客戶保留的報告，
and grab meeting notes from your colleagues.
並從同事那裡獲取會議筆記。
Before you know it, they have a lot to work with.
在您不知道之前，他們有很多事情要處理。
But now, you've got a different kind of challenge.
但現在，你面臨了一種不同的挑戰。
With all of these different sources,
有了所有這些不同的
how do you make sense of it all?
來源，您如何理解這一切？
Not everyone has training on how to analyze data,
並非每個人都有關如何分析資料的訓練
and even for those that do,
，即使對於那些有這樣做的人
it isn't always easy to pull clear insights from raw data.
來說，從原始資料中獲得清晰的見解並不總是容易。
But data analysis can be an incredibly valuable tool.
但是數據分析可能是一個非常有價值的工具。
Why?
為什麼？
Because data can help you make the best
因為數據可以幫助您做出最佳
and most informed decisions,
且最明智的決策，
and it can provide support
並且可以為
for your point of view on any given issue.
您對任何特定問題的觀點提供支持。
Now, with AI,
現在，使用 AI，
even people whose eyes would normally glaze over
即使是通常會看到試算表
at the site of a spreadsheet
位置的人，也
can take advantage of the power of data insights.
可以利用資料洞察的力量。
Gemini can take messy data and tell you what it all means.
雙子座可以獲取雜亂的數據並告訴您這一切意味著什麼。
It can even make sense
它甚至可以同時
of different types of data at the same time,
理解不同類型的數據，例
like customer retention numbers and survey feedback.
如客戶保留數和調查問卷反饋。
AI can make the most frustrating
AI 可以使
and time-consuming parts of data analysis
數據分析中最令人沮喪和耗時
just fade into the background.
的部分變為後台。
You can even create visualizations
您甚至可以創建視覺化
to communicate your findings.
來傳達您的發現。
You can also do more complex analysis in new ways
您還可以使用
using everyday language with Gemini in Sheets,
Gemini in Sheets 使用日常語言以新的方式進行更複雜的分析，
and you can accelerate data cleaning
並且可以加速資料清理
and uncover patterns between different data sources.
並發現不同資料來源之間的模式。
It'll even troubleshoot complicated formulas for you.
它甚至可以為您解決複雜的公式。
All this means that you can discover valuable insights
所有這些意味著您可以在通常所花
in a fraction of the time it would normally take.
費的時間的一小部分內發現寶貴的見解。
Now, you might be thinking,
現在，您可能會想，
"If Gemini can do all this analysis for me,
「如果雙子座能夠為我做所有這些分析
what do I have to do?"
，我該怎麼辦？」
Well, first you still have to ask
好吧，首先你仍然必須問有
really good questions about the data.
關數據的真正好問題。
Sometimes it helps to start broad
有時，從廣泛開始了
to understand the biggest trends
解最大的趨勢
and the most important conclusions,
和最重要的結論，
and then drill down into the details.
然後深入研究細節有幫助。
Second, if you make a discovery
第二，如果您發現一個
or find an interesting insight,
發現或發現有趣的見
it's really up to you to understand the implications
解，真的取決於您來了解影響
and make the right business decisions.
並做出正確的商業決策。
And lastly, you'll always need to verify the findings
最後，您將始終需要驗證發現以確
to ensure their accuracy.
保其準確性。
Another thing to consider is data privacy.
另一件需要考慮的事情是數據隱私。
The goal and rule is simple,
目標和規則很簡單，切
never input confidential data into a public AI tool
勿將機密數據輸入到公共 AI 工具中
and always consult your company's policies
，並始終諮詢公司有
on acceptable use of AI tools.
關可接受使用 AI 工具的政策。
Now, if you do need to work with sensitive data,
現在，如果您確實需要處理敏感數據，
you have two main options.
則有兩個主要選項。
First, see if your company has an enterprise-grade AI tool.
首先，查看您的公司是否具有企業級 AI 工具。
The second option is to check the settings
第二個選項是檢查您正在使用
of the public tool that you're using.
的公用工具的設置。
You can opt out of data collection
您可以根據需要選擇退出數據收集
or adjust your privacy controls as needed.
或調整隱私控制項。
Understanding these controls isn't just about privacy,
了解這些控制項不僅僅是關於隱私
it's about giving you the knowledge and confidence
，而且還有關為您提供使用
to analyze data with AI.
AI 分析資料的知識和信心。
By the end of this course,
在本課程結束時，
you'll be able to use Gemini
您將能夠使用 Gemini 發
to discover the most critical insights
現隱藏在數
hidden in an ocean of data.
據海洋中最重要的見解。
So, let's dive in.
所以，讓我們深入探討。